hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so now um I'm going to discuss
a scenario uh which uh is asked quite
often and I have come across many
questions on this particular scenario
and the question was how can we find all
the links uh which are present on the
page using tosa right so uh either it
could be the number of links uh it could
be the number of buttons or it could be
number of checkboxes any particular
element right so all of these um are
some common elements like uh the link
would have uh some common property like
the tag would be uh the value a which
implies that it is a link similarly for
buttons there could be a common property
value so using this common property
values you can find all the elements
which are present on that particular
page which have got these common
properties okay you can also modify some
of the property like the ID value uh
where you can find some static part of
that particular ID value which remains
constant and then other parts may be
changing but using that static part you
can find all all um the elements which
matches that particular ID property
value so this is how you you can find a
solution to this particular problem
let's pick up an example and let's uh
look at a real-time example on how we
can go ahead and uh find a solution for
this right so here uh the scenario is uh
I've got the source demo website and I
am in the product speech where I've got
a number of different products right and
here what I to verify is uh there are
six products displayed on this page now
there are various ways of uh going about
this right so either uh you can go and
scan each of these elements um and then
you can verify uh by putting a buffer
count and then uh calculating how many
products are displayed on the page but
what if there are hundreds of products
okay so these are basically links um all
of these titles which you see are uh the
product links okay and if I got 100
products on this page then this
particular solution may be difficult
right you you don't want to scan 100
elements uh which are of similar nature
right which are particularly similar
links now instead of that uh we can opt
for a much efficient and easier solution
okay so let me show you um how you can
do that so here uh let's first uh go
ahead and scan this application so what
we need to do uh is we need to just scan
one of these elements and then we have
to modify the properties which can match
all the other elements on this page of
uh the similar nature in our case uh
these are the product links right so
we'll go
here and then uh we will pick up one of
the products let's pick up the first
product okay Source laabs backpack
so I can find this link here I can
select this uh it's a unique uh item you
can see and if I go into the technical
properties you can see the tag value is
a which will never change for a link and
then uh if I look at the ID it is itmore
4ore titlecore link right now if I look
at the other links right uh for example
this bike light if I select this you
will see uh the tag uh property value is
still a but the ID is changing okay the
ID is now item undor zore titlecore link
okay but if you noticed uh the last part
of the of this particular value is
actually constant right so the title
underscore link is constant and the item
underscore the number is changing okay
so for this it is item _ 0 and if I look
back at my previous element then it is
item underscore 4 but the last part is
still titlecore link okay so uh we can
modify this uh ID value so that it
matches all the elements uh which have
got this constant value which is
titlecore link okay and then tosa will
be able to find all the links which have
got this particular ID okay okay so
let's go ahead and first select this
particular link and then we will change
it in our module attribute here I'm
going to name this uh called products
the name of the module and then I'm
going to save
this and close this and then let's go to
our module attribute here I am going to
call this just
product okay because it is a generic
product link um and it's not any
specific link so I'm changing it to a
generic name and then I want to change
the ID of this particular product okay
so we want to keep the constant part
here titlecore link but we will uh
remove this itmore 4 underscore and
replace it with a regular expression so
that it can match all the other elements
which this particular ID
okay also what we want to do is uh we
want to change the cardinality
here okay so that uh we can use this
link uh any number of times okay uh in
our test case and then uh we can also
add a configuration parameter called
explicit
name and we can set it to True here so
that we can uh change the module
attribute name from the test step itself
okay so these are two additional
properties uh if you want to perform
some action on the link or you want to
change the name of the link and click on
these links uh repeatedly then you need
to change the cardinality and the
explicit name property okay now if I go
back to my module and then um I create a
test case for this so let's pick up one
folder and here I'm going to create a
test case called check
products okay and then uh we are going
to add our module products right here
and now uh what we want to do is we want
to get the count of these links present
on the page which will give me U the
number of products okay so uh what I can
do is I can use something called the
result count so this will return me the
count of all of these module attributes
or these links which are present in the
page okay and then I can just uh store
it into um a buffer so um I'm going to
call this bcore
products okay and then um we are going
to change the action mode to buffer here
right so it will basically get the
result count and then it will store it
in bore products right so that's our
first part now due to the cardinality
factor which we changed from 0 to 1 to 0
to n now you can see repeatedly this
model attribute will be added also we
can change the name of this uh product
right here okay so I can change it to
anything um let's remove it right now we
don't require this now the next thing
which uh I want to do here is um I want
to verify whether this result count is
equal to a particular number okay so in
my case it is six I want to verify
whether the result count is six so I
will do that before that let me change
the test step name here so I will say
get product
count so now let's go back to our test
case and we are going to add another
test step here and that is tbox
evaluation tool okay so this way we can
evaluate any particular expression uh we
are going to evaluate whether our buffer
be underscore
products is equals equals 6
so this is an expression it will
evaluate this expression and if it is
correct then it will pass otherwise it
will fail okay so I will say here check
number of
products
is six
okay so this way uh I can get the result
count of all the uh product links on my
page and then I can also verify um the
number number of products okay using
that result count so let's go ahead and
run this and let's verify whether we're
getting the same result as expected uh
run this in
scratchbook and then um the test case
will pass we can go ahead and look in
our scratchbook
logs okay so here you can see bore
products was set to
six and then here U six equal equal 6
was evaluated to True okay so the
expression was
correct so this way I could verify the
number of product links uh and that in
turn told me how many products are being
displayed on the page similarly You Can
Count uh all the links which are present
on your page you just need to change the
module attribute if I go to the module
attribute of the link and I just remove
the ID property from here then it will
return me all the links present on this
page so there are number of possible
scenarios uh in which this particular
way could be used to uh automate uh your
particular scenario it as I said it
could be uh for the links if you have
got number of common check boxes on the
page and you have to check all the
checkboxes you can also do this using
this way so as I said uh it could be
used in many different
scenarios that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video